Inventory of the Mme. E. de Basily-Callimaki papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Mme. E. de Basily-Callimaki papers
1867-1913.
65012
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (2.0 linear feet)
The collection contains materials relating to French and Western European art history, and to Jean Baptiste Isabey, the French miniaturist, in correspondence, writings, notes, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia. Includes a draft of the biography of Isabey by E. de Basily-Callimaki.
Basily-Callimaki, E. de, Mme.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1965.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Russian art critic and author.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, notes, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to French and Western European art history, and to Jean Baptiste Isabey, the French miniaturist. Includes a draft of the biography of Isabey by E. de Basily-Callimaki.
Related Collection(s)
Nikolaĭ Aleksandrovich Bazili papers, Hoover Institution Archives Lascelle Meserve de Basily papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Isabey, Jean Baptiste, 1767-1855.; Art.
- Handwritten notebooks with lists of art objects, and an introduction to an art history essay concerning Jean Baptiste Isabey (4 notebooks), 1908-1910 (Folder 1: 1-2)
- Correspondence and receipts from European booksellers (in France, Russia, and Austro-Hungarian Empire), 1909-1912. (Folder 1: 3-4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes Catalogue de la Bibliothéque N.G. Egoroff et des acquisitions récentes, Moscow, 1910
- Research and reference materials for the book; correspondence, documents on miniatures, catalogues, notes, and clippings, 1800-1913 (Folder 1: 5-8)
- Chapter drafts of the Isabey monograph, circa 1900 (Folder 1: 9-11)
- Chapter drafts of the Isabey monograph, circa 1900 (Contd.) (Folder 2: 1-12)
- Chapter drafts of the Isabey monograph, circa 1900 (Contd.) (Folder 3: 1-2)
- Hotel Drouot auction catalogues of Mme. de Basily's estate, Paris, November 1913, including fine art objects such as paintings by Delacroix and Isabey, tapestries, Oriental rugs, 18th century furniture, faiences and porcelains, and sculptures (one by A. Rodin) (Folder 3: 3)
- Beaux Arts, Gazette, Paris, featuring write-up of Mme. de Basily's monograph on Isabey, 1910 (Folder 3: 4)
- Photo lithograph "Old Landing Place, Lake Como,", 1919 (Folder 3: 5)
- Photo lithographs by Familia Regală la Sinaia, Atelier A. Thalsky, circa 1900 (Folder 3: 6)
- Collection of brass sealing stamps, medallion of Victor Hugo, and pendant, circa 1900 (Folder 3: 7)
- Unbound published copy of Mme. de Basily's monograph of Jean Baptiste Isabey, 1909 (Box 4)
- Bound published copy of Mme. de Basily's monograph of Jean Baptiste Isabey, 1909 (Box 5)